Guide to the Community Service Society Archives
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XVII: Files, 1970-1986
  - Subseries XVII.2: Reports. Pamphlets. Clippings, A-Z
    - Computers In The Schools Anne Mckay et al. 1984 66pp. (Box 583)
    - "Connections", house organization started with "fall '86" issue, 10/86 (Box 583)
    - Continuing Programs Task Force, Report to Executive Com. 4/2/79 (Box 583)
    - Criminal & Juvenile Justice Com. '1979-81 Minutes, Memos, Proposals (Box 583)
    - Day Care and the Working Poor by McMurray & Kazanjian 1982 139pp. (Box 584)
    - Preliminary Report on the Day Care Eligibility Study, 1980 (Box 584)
    - Demonstrating Community-Based Long-Term Care In The United States: An Evaluation Research Perspective. by Francis C. Caro, Ph.D., Institute for Social Welfare Research, CSS, May 1986. (Box 584)
    - Education Committee Minutes etc. 1980-1981 (Box 584)
    - Education for Expectant Parents, Directory of (NYC, Nassau, Westchester) 1972 57pp. $1.00 (Box 584)
    - Employment"Chasing The American Dream" 11/80 - NAACP - CSS Study re Minorities & Jobs 1980-83 includes 65 page "Working Paper" by Sumnar M. Rosen of 1984-85 "New York Works!" (Box 584)
    - Executive Committee, 1988 (Box 584)
    - Family Care of the Elderly Frankfather Smith, Caro - 1981? 175pp. (Box 584)
    - Financial Accountants Reports '61-'74, '83 (Box 585)
    - Financial Statements (Box 585)
    - Forty Forgotten Families, a study of Young AFDC Families 1965 Friday Memo, etc. by B. Beck 1/3/83 - 7/23/84 (Box 585)
    - Goldberg Dissertation re CSS 75 Xerox Copy & Comment (Box 586)
    - Health & Nutrition Committee f80-'81 (Box 586)
    - The Heights: A Community Housing Strategy...for homeless people. *(See Homeless II) (Box 586)
    - History of CSS, by Vida S. Grayson: (Box 586)
    - Reminiscences of Stanley Powell Davies 1981 141 pp. (Box 586)
    - Reminiscences of Clare M. Tousley 1981 260 pp. (Box 586)
    - Reminiscences of Ollie A. Randall 1981 53 pp. (Box 586)
    - Home Care In NYC 1985 - re Aging by Caro & Blank 18 pp. (Box 586)
    - Homeless: "Alternatives To The Welfare Hotel" by Victor Bach & Renee Steinhagen 1987 54 pp. "Financial Management Systems II 87 pp. n.d. (Box 586)
    - Homeless II: (Box 587)
      - Developing Shelter Models for The Homeless '85, The Making of America's Homeless '84, Struggling to Survive in a Welfare Hotel '84, Hardship in the Heartland '84, Hotel Watch '83, The New Mendicacy - Homeless in NYC '81, Homeless Youth in NYC 77, ONE YEAR LATER, The Homeless Poor in NYC, 1982 ca. 80 pp. (Box 587)
    - Housing & Urban Development:
      - Minutes f80-'81 (Box 587)
      - Report of In Rem Task Force 12/29/80 (Box 587)
      - Alternative Management 80-81 sep. Folder (Box 587)
      - Etc. (Box 587)
    - Housing:
      - Saving Homes for the Poor *(See Homeless II) (Box 587)
      - Reforming The Community Development Program, 1979 *(See Housing & Urban Development) (Box 587)
    - Life in Public Housing Equals Tenants Plus Management 1971-40+pp. by Alexander Greendale (Box 587)
    - Housing & Urban Development Committee Minutes *(See Housing & Urban Development) (Box 587)
    - Income Maintenance Committee Minutes etc. 79-81 (Box 587)
    - The Intellectually Superior Child In a Deprived Social Area - Appendix: "The Pursuit of Promise" 1967 (Box 587)
    - Jobs & Economic Development Committee 1980-81 (Box 587)
    - Juvenile Injustice: Dilemmas of The Family Court System (Box 587)
    - Life in Public Housing (Box 588)
    - Making The Punishment Fit the Crime a Proposal for Determinate Sentences for Juveniles 1976 (Box 588)
    - Medical Care Prices & The Consumer Price Index by G. Ellenbogen 1973 (Box 588)
    - Methadone Maintenance Treatment In New York City Com. on Youth & Justice 6/75, 76 pp. (Box 588)
    - Mentally Disabled Adults in Community Setting, Quality of Life of, "Interim Report" by Baxter & Hopper, 24 pp., 1979 (Box 588)
    - Mentally Disabled, Cost Effectiveness in Community Care of The. by Francis G. Caro 11/80 (Box 588)
    - Quality of Life of Mentally Disabled Adults in Community Settings. by Baxter & Hopper 9/79 *(See Mentally Disabled Adults) (Box 588)
    - Natural Supports New York City: A Problem Census and Social Report A.&J. Stimson, E.J. Mullen, 10/70 265 pp. (Box 588)
    - NYC's Poverty Budget, analysis by NOVA Inst. 9/84 184 pp. (Box 588)
    - Newsworthy - Articles about CSS 1986 87. (Box 588)
    - "News, In The": (Box 589)
      - Winter 1983 Selected publicity (Box 589)
      - Summer " (Box 589)
      - 1984-85 (Box 589)
      - 1986-87 (Box 589)
    - Not Without Hope, A Report & Recommendations on Family Relocation Com. on Housing 3/58 (Box 589)
    - "People" (Box 589)
    - Personnel Com. of the Board, Minutes 10/83 - 2/86 (Box 589)
    - Planning Com. (2 Folders):
      - 1981 (Box 589)
      - Report on CSS 79-8 1 *(See Report & Planning Committee on CSS) (Box 589)
    - Post-Hospital Care Arrangements for the Functionally Disabled Elderly (Box 590)
    - Poverty, changing Views of ca. 1984 43 pp. (Box 590)
    - Private Lives/Public Spaces Baxter & Hopper 1981 121 pp. (Box 590)
    - Program Agenda - Summary Report 10, '79 (Box 590)
    - Public Affairs, The Bureau of, Cause, Character & Course 1959 - 38 pp. (Box 590)
    - Plan of Organization & Procedures for Public Affairs Program 1972 (Box 590)
    - Publications, Misc. (Box 590)
    - Report (on CSS) "Progress Notes, 1-3, '81; Quarterly 7-9, '82 4-6, '83; 10-12, ‘83; 1-3 & 4-6, ‘84 (Box 590)
    - Report on CSS Program Activities 12/78 (Box 590)
    - RSVP-SERVE Neswletter (Box 590)
    - Single Parent Family Project (Box 590)
    - Social Policy Issues Affecting The Poor by Georgia L. McMurray 1983 37 pp. (Box 590)
    - Strategies for Social Intervention Young, Taran, Weis, Mullen 1970 Draft Part of CSS Study (Box 591)
    - Study Com., Report To, By Com. on Public Affairs 1970 110 pp. MA Place in The Community for Every Man" (Box 591)
    - Study Com., Report To Trustees 1/27/71 (Box 591)
    - Summer Camp Program for One-Parent Families, a Report by Nancy Rearing, October 1975 $3.00 64 pp. (Box 591)
    - Supporting Families Who Care For Severely Disabled Children At Home (Box 591)
    - Survey of Residents' Perceptions of Neighborhood Services In The Southeast Bronx & Central Harlem by Louis Harris & Assoc. Inc. 1979 ca. 80 pp. (Box 591)
    - Technical Assistance Technical Assistance Guide 1986 (Box 591)
    - Trustees, Board of Minutes, Etc. '69 - '84 (Box 592)
    - Trustees, Board of Minutes 1977 (Box 592)
    - Trustees, Board of Minutes 9/77 - 2/76 (Box 592)
    - Trustees, Boards of Minutes from leather binders 6/76 1/76 with finance & Real Estate Com. of The Board 1960-69, 1 vol. (Box 593)
    - Trustees, Board of Minutes annual Board and Members Unemployment Insurance and the Low Income Worker by Linda R. Wolf Jones, 1985. (Box 593)
    - Washington Heights/Inwood Neighborhoods" Assessment of Health Care Needs - North Manhattan Health Action Group Report, 2/84 116 pp. (Box 593)
    - Work Environment Study 4/83, 30 pp. (Box 593)
    - Workshops in Organizing (4 pamphlets) (Box 593)
    - Youth Enter Prizes by J. Polner 1983 & Chasing The American Dream 1981 (Box 593)
    - Youth Training and Employment Programs - for Com. on Youth Correction, by Sophie Engle 1967 (Box 593)
    - Youth Offenders: (Box 593)
    - Engaging The Serious Youth Offender in Employment, Training (Box 593)
    - Project Real (Box 593)
    - 1984 (Box 593)
    - Jones, Hoffman, Llanos (Box 593)
- Series XVIII:Legal and Financial Matters, and H. Dogue Materials
  Note: For a detailed list of contents of these Folders, see the following section "Folder Conte
  - Subseries XVIII.1: Legal & Financial Matters
    - Adopt-a-family (Box 594)
    - American Foundation for the Blind *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #607) (Box 594)
    - Annual Printing Report (Haskins & Sells) (Box 594)
    - Annual Reports (Box 594)
    - Audit Committee (Box 594)
    - Auditing--Haskins & Sells (Box 594)
    - Bank Accounts Courtesy Account (Box 595)
    - Bank of New York (Box 595)
    - Banks Trust Company (Box 595)
    - Board of Managers Meetings--United Charities (Box 595)
    - Boys House and Dosoris *(See: H. Dogue Materials Box #607) (Box 595)
    - Budgetary Process in CSS (Box 595)
    - Caldwalder-Wickersham & Taft (Box 595)
    - Capital & Operating Cash Funds (Box 595)
    - Capital Funds General and Restricted (Box 595)
    - Certificate of consolidation of CSS (Box 595)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank-Letters 1956-1973 (Box 596)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank Savings Account(Opp. Shop) (Box 596)
    - Chemical Bank & Trust Co. (Box 596)
    - Childeren's Rights Project (Box 596)
    - Citibank Archer Ave. Project Checking Account (Box 596)
    - Citibank Capital Fund Savings Account (Box 596)
    - Closed Bank Accounts (Box 596)
    - Community Action Program *(See H. Dogue Materials Box # 607) (Box 596)
    - Community Board Project (Box 596)
    - CSS Board of Trustees *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #608) (Box 596)
    - CSS Briefing on Fiscal Year 1983 (Box 596)
    - CSS Budget 1973-1974 (Box 596)
    - CSS Bulletin Board (Box 596)
    - "CSS Fair" held at Rockefeller Center (Box 596)
    - CSS Financial Study (Box 596)
    - CSS Inventories (Box 597)
    - CSS Miscellaneous (Box 597)
    - CSS News (Box 597)
    - CSS Program Agenda (Box 597)
    - CSS Proposed Budjets 1967-1973 (Box 597)
    - CSS Publication AfProgram (Box 597)
    - CSS Report July 1982 (Box 597)
    - Confidential (Box 597)
    - Continuity in Care for Impaired Older Persons (Box 597)
    - Department of Finance (Box 597)
    - The Dime Savings Bank of Brooklyn (Box 597)
    - District 1199 (Union) *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #608) (Box 597)
    - Donations from Mrs. Colin G. Fink *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #608) (Box 597)
    - Donors *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #608) (Box 597)
    - DSS-CSS Collaborative Project (Box 598)
    - Expense Definitions (Box 598)
    - Fees Miscellaneous (Box 598)
    - Financial Assistance Information (Box 598)
    - Financial Assistance Fund (Box 598)
    - Financial Miscellaneous (Box 598)
    - Friendship Center *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #608) (Box 598)
    - Functions/001 (Box 598)
    - Fund Raising Gifts Received by CSS Greater New York Fund *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #609) (Box 598)
    - Haley, William, Esq.Papers *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #609) (Box 599)
    - Head Start (Box 599)
    - Homemaker Service (Box 599)
    - International Press Ball (Box 599)
    - Investments Jamaica Service Program 1975-1977 (Box 599)
    - Kings County Savings Bank (Capital fund/Savings Account) (Box 600)
    - Ladies' Christian Union *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #609) (Box 600)
    - Landlork/Tenant Forms plus instructions (Box 600)
    - Lay Staff Relationship 1975 (Box 600)
    - Legal Case (L. McMillan et al. 1970-Legal Papers) (Box 600)
    - Legal Matters (Box 600)
    - Marine Midland Grace Trust Co. of NY (Box 600)
    - Memos to Data Processing Unit (Box 600)
    - Mortgages (Box 601)
    - Neighborhood Conservation ProgramCity Contract (Box 601)
    - Neighborhood Conservation Project (Box 601)
    - New York Bank for Savings (Box 601)
    - New York School of Social Work *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #610) (Box 601)
    - New York Times Neediest Cases Fund *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #610) (Box 601)
    - Older Persons Service SEE Natural Supts. (Box 601)
    - Opportunity Shop *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #610) (Box 602)
    - Out-of-State Placement Documents (Box 602)
    - Placement of Children in Foster Care (Box 602)
    - Project for Addicted Servicemen *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #611) (Box 602)
    - Project Forms (Informational Records)Blanks (Box 602)
    - Property (= real estate) *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #611) (Box 602)
    - Reports:
      - Camp Scholarships 1978 (Box 602)
      - Community Planning Board 1976 (Box 602)
      - Purchase Requisitions (Box 602)
    - Rockefeller Brothers' Fund (Box 602)
    - Salaries--Unclassified Positions (Box 602)
    - Sale of Securities--Blank Forms (Box 603)
    - School Project (Box 603)
    - (The) Seamen's Bank for Savings (Box 603)
    - Senior Advisory Service Projects (Box 604)
    - Senior Advisors Service (Box 604)
    - Senior Advisory Service:
      - 10/1/66-9/30/67 (Box 604)
      - 10/1/67-9/30/68 (Box 604)
      - 10/1/68-11/30/69 (Box 604)
    - SAS(Senior Advisory Service) 1969 (Box 605)
    - SERVE *(See H. Dogue Materials Box #612-615) (Box 605)
    - Serving The Aging (Box 605)
    - State Supreme Court of NY--Briefs (Box 605)
    - Stock Confirmations (Box 605)
    - Stock Gifts--Confidential (Box 605)
    - Stock Gift Folder: II (Box 605)
    - Taxes (Box 606)
    - Thompkins Square House *(See also H. Dogue Materials Box #616) (Box 606)
    - United Charities Building (Box 606)
    - United Charities Mortgage Interest (Box 606)
    - United States Trust Co. (Box 606)
    - Wood, Struthers, & Winthrop Investment Advisors (Box 606)
  - Subseries XVIII.2: H.Dogue
    - American Foundation for the Blind (Box 607)
    - Boys House and Dosoris (Box 607)
    - Community Action Program (Box 607)
    - CSS Board of Trustees (Box 608)
    - District 1199 (Union) (Box 608)
    - Donations from Mrs. Colin G. Fink (Box 608)
    - Donors (Box 608)
    - Friendship Center (Box 608)
    - Greater New York Fund (Box 609)
    - Haley, William, Esq. Papers (Box 609)
    - Ladies’ Christian Union (Box 609)
    - New York School of Social Work (Box 610)
    - New York Times Neediest Cases Fund (Box 610)
    - Opportunity Shop (Box 610)
    - Project for Addicted Servicemen (Box 611)
    - Property (=real estate) (Box 611)
    - SERVE (Box 612-615)
    - Tompkins Square House (Box 616)
    - CSS Publications:
      - Address by John S. Kennedy at the Opening of the United Charities Building, March 6, 1893 (Box 616)
      - Senior Advisory Service for Public Housing Tenants, 12/69 (Box 616)
      - Status Report Special on the Federal Budget Process: Session Alert, November 22, 1982 (Box 616)
      - Thinking About Alternatives, by Kim Hopper, July 1981 (Box 616)
      - Treatment Programs for New York City's Youthful Drug Abusers, Part 2, by Suzanne W. Todd, January 1974 (Box 616)